Come on, out of the way.
Move yourself, please. Coming through.
- There!
- That's it, excuse me, sir.
Madame Vastra, thank God.
I'll wager you've not seen anything
like this before!
Well...
not since I was a little girl.
- Big fellow, isn't he?
- Dinosaurs were mostly this size.
I do believe it's a "she".
- No, they weren't, I've seen fossils.
- I was there.
Well, that's all well and good
but what's this dinosaur fellow
doing in the Thames?
It must have time-travelled. Jenny?
Time-travelled?
Is it choking?
There seems to be something
lodged in its throat.
Well, how could it time-travel?
I don't know.
Perhaps it was something it ate.
Stand back. Stand back, stand back.
Well, it's just laid an egg.
It dropped a blue box marked
"Police" out of its mouth.
Your grasp of biology troubles me.
- It's the Tardis.
- It would seem so.
We'll take care of this, Inspector.
But what if that thing
goes on the rampage?
Place these lanterns
on the shore line and bridges,
encircling the creature...
twenty foot intervals.
What will they do?
They will emit a signal that will incline it
to remain within their circumference.
Jenny, Strax! With me.
So it's him, then? The Doctor.
A giant dinosaur from the distant past
has just vomited a blue box
from outer space.
This is not a day for
jumping to conclusions.
Strax, if you wouldn't mind?
Hello?
Exit the box and surrender to the glory
of the Sontaran Empire!
Shush.
Doctor?
I was being chased by a giant dinosaur
but I think I managed to give it the slip.
Sleepy?
Sir?
Bashful? Sneezy? Dopey?
Grumpy!
Oh, you two.
The green one and the not-green one.
Or it could be the other way round,
I mustn't pre-judge.
Oh, you remember, uh...
Thingy. The, uh...
The not... The not-me one.
The asking-questions one.
Names, not my area.
Clara!
It might be Clara, it might not be.
It's a lottery.
- It is Clara.
- Well, I'm not ruling it out!
Oi! Big man! Shut it!
Oh! You've got a dinosaur, too!
Big woman, sorry.
Doctor, listen to me.
You... You need to calm down.
- I'm not flirting, by the way.
- I think something's gone wrong.
Wrong? What's gone wrong?
Have you regenerated?
I remember you!
You're Handles! You used to be
a little... a little robot head
and now you...
You've really let yourself go.
Reduce the frequency.
- I'm sorry?
- Your sonic lanterns, turn them down.
- You're giving her a headache.
- Giving who a headache?
My lady friend.
Just an expression, don't get any ideas.
But how do you know?
Come on, Clara!
You know that I speak dinosaur.
He's not Clara. I'm Clara.
Well, you're very similar heights.
Maybe you should wear labels.
Why...
Why are you all doing that?
Why are you all going dark?
- And wobbly, stop that.
- I don't think we are.
Never mind! Everyone, take five.
What do we do?
I don't understand, who is he?
Where's the Doctor?
Right here. That's him.
That's the Doctor.
Well, then. Here we go again.
It's simply misunderstand able to me.
I don't know what it is.
Who invented this room?
Doctor, please, you have to lie down.
It doesn't make any sense.
Look, it's only got a bed in it.
Why is there only a bed in it?
Because it's a bedroom,
it's for sleeping in.
- Okay, what do you do when you're awake?
- You leave the room.
So you've got a whole room
for not being awake in?
But what's the point?
You're just missing the room!
And don't look in that mirror,
it's absolutely furious.
Doctor, please. You have to lie down,
you keep passing out.
Well, off course I keep passing out,
there's all these beds!
Why do you keep talking like that?
What's gone wrong with your accent?
Nothing's gone wrong with her accent.
You sound the same, it's spreading.
You all sound all English,
now you've all developed a fault!
Doctor, I need your help with something.
Finally, someone who can talk properly.
I'm having difficulty sleeping.
Oh? Oh, well, I wouldn't bother
with that, I never bother with sleep,
I just do standy-up catnaps.
Oh, really? How interesting.
And when do you do those?
Well, generally whenever anyone else
starts talking.
I like to skip ahead to my bits,
it saves time.
Oh. Save me time, Doctor,
project an image of perfect sleep
into the center of my mind.
What, you want a psychic link with me?
The size of my brain, it would be like
dropping a piano on you.
Be gentle, then.
I'll try. Brace yourself.
Piano.
I love monkeys, they're so funny!
Oh, I see!
So people are monkeys now, are they?
No, dear, people are apes.
Men are monkeys.
- So what now?
- He needs rest.
- So what do we do? How do we fix him?
- Fix him?
How do we change him back?
Jenny, I will be in my chamber.
Would you be kind enough
to fetch my veil?
Why? Are we expecting strangers?
It would seem there is already one here.
What have I done wrong?
- The dinosaur doesn't seem very happy.
- What's wrong with it?
I don't know.
The Doctor's the one
that speaks dinosaur.
Excuse me, ma'am, the wife
doesn't like to be kept waiting.
Where did he get that face?
Why has it got lines on it?
It's brand-new.
How can his hair be all grey?
He only just got it.
It's still him, ma'am,
you saw him change.
- I know. I do. I... I know that.
- Good.
- It's just...
- What?
Nothing.
If... If Vastra changed,
if she was different,
if she wasn't the person that you liked?
I don't like her, ma'am, I love her.
And as to different, well, she's a lizard.
I am alone.
The world which shook at my feet
and the trees
and the sky have gone
and I am alone now...
Alone.
Are you translating?
The wind bites now
and the world is grey
and I am alone.
Can't see me. Doesn't see me.
Can't see me.
You can't see it?
I think all of London can see it.
Boy? Madame Vastra is waiting.
- Okay, whatever.
- I will convey you to her chamber.
May I take your coat?
- Not wearing a coat.
- What's all that?
Clothes.
- May I take your clothes?
- Probably not.
- Are you wearing a hat?
- It's hair.
No, I think it's a hat,
would you like me to check?
- It's not real, of course.
- What is it, then?
- The government.
- The government?
Yeah, up to their usual tricks.
It's a dinosaur, Alf. A real dinosaur.
I wouldn't put it past them.
You don't half talk a lot of rubbish, Alfie.
See you don't stay out too late, now.
- You know me.
- Yes, I do.
It's the neck, that's what's wrong with it.
It just don't look realistic.
- You have good eyes.
- I do, as it happens. Very good eyes.
They're my greatest gift.
- I accept.
- What's that for?
Your gift. I have bad eyes.
And then?
- Why are you wearing your veil?
- And then?
And then we got swallowed by a big
dinosaur. You probably noticed.
- How did it happen?
- I don't know. I don't know, we were...
crashing about everywhere.
The Doctor was gone,
the Tardis went haywire.
He's not gone. He's upstairs.
- Okay, he changed.
- He regenerated. Renewed himself.
Renewed, fine.
Such a cynical smile.
I'm not smiling.
Not outwardly. But I am accustomed
to seeing through a veil.
How have I amused you?
You said renewed. He doesn't...
He doesn't look renewed, he looks older.
- You thought he was young?
- He looked young.
He looked like your dashing young
gentleman friend. Your lover, even.
- Shut up!
- But he is the Doctor.
He has walked this universe
for centuries untold,
he has seen stars fall to dust.
You might as well flirt
with a mountain range.
- I did not flirt with him.
- He flirted with you.
- How?
- He looked young.
Who do you think that was for?
- Me?
- Everyone.
I wear a veil as he wore a face,
for the same reason.
What reason?
The oldest reason there is for anything.
To be accepted.
Jenny and I are married,
yet for appearances' sake,
we maintain a pretence in public
that she is my maid.
Doesn't exactly explain
why I'm pouring tea in private.
- Hush, now.
- Good pretence, isn't it?
I wear a veil to keep from view
what many are pleased to call
my disfigurement.
I do not wear it
as a courtesy to such people
but as a judgment
on the quality of their hearts.
Are you judging me?
The Doctor regenerated in your presence.
The young man disappeared,
the veil lifted.
He trusted you. Are you judging him?
How dare you? How dare you?
Door. Boring! Not me.
Me!
Marcus Aurelius, Roman Emperor,
last of the Five Good
and stoic philosopher.
Superlative bass guitarist. The Doctor
really knows how to put a band together.
And the only pin-up I ever had
on my wall when I was 15,
only one I ever had.
I am not sure who you think you're
talking to right now, Madam Vastra,
but I have never had the slightest
interest in pretty young men.
And for the record, if there was anybody
who could flirt with a mountain range,
she's probably standing in front of you
right now! Oh!
Just because my pretty face
has turned your head,
do not assume
that I am so easily distracted.
Whoo!
Sorry.
Well. Goodness me!
The lake has ruffled at last.
I have often wondered what you'd be like
when you lost your temper.
Oi! Married.
The Doctor needs us,
you more than anyone.
He is lost in the ruin of himself
and we must bring him home.
When did you stop wearing your veil?
When you stopped seeing it.
Oi! Oi!
Hey! Big, sexy woman!
Hey!
Sorry. Sorry, it's all my fault.
My time machine got stuck
in your throat, it happens.
I brought you along by accident.
That's mostly howl meet girls
but don't worry,
I promise I will get you home.
I swear, whatever it takes...
I will keep you safe.
You will be home again.
Stop that. Who's doing that?
No, don't do that!
- That came from the river.
- The dinosaur!
Strax! Bring the carriage, now!
Ah!
Halt!
Sorry, I'm going to have to relieve you
of your pet.
- You're what?
- Shut up, I was talking to the horse!
What are you doing?
Forward!
Out of the way, human scum. Hyah!
Jurassic emergency!
Hvah!
Left! No, no, right, right, right, right!
Sorry, it's my new hands,
I can't tell them apart.
- What do you think's happened?
- I don't know but I fear devilment!
- Should we not have told the Doctor?
- He's not ready to leave his bed.
Watch it on the corners,
it's a bit slippy up here!
- Strax, come on, Strax! That's better!
- Hyah, Hyah!
Sorry, sorry, I'm sorry.
Sorry, sorry.
Whoa.
The Doctor! What's he doing here?
There is trouble.
Where else would he be?
She was scared.
She was scared and alone.
I brought her here
and look what they did.
Who or what could have done this thing?
No.
I'm sorry?
No. That is not the question,
that is not where we start.
The question is how?
The flesh itself has been combusted...
No, no, shut up!
What do you all have for brains?
Pudding? Look at you.
Why can't I meet a decent species?
Planet of the pudding-brains!
Doctor... I know you're upset
but you need to calm down
and talk to us. What is the question?
A dinosaur is burning
in the heart of London.
Nothing left but smoke and flame.
The question is
have there been any similar murders?
Yes. Yes, by the Goddess, there have!
Look at them all, gawking.
Question two.
If all the pudding-brains are gawking,
then what is he?
He seems remarkably unmoved
by the available spectacle.
Do you think that's whoever...
- What he's doing? He'll drown!
- I very much doubt it.
- Why?
- There has been a murder.
The Doctor has taken up the case.
If we are to see him again,
we must do the same.
Come on, Earthling scum!
Position it here.
Easy, now. That's it. Careful.
Don't get it scratched
or you and all your bloodline
will be obliterated from time and space.
Strax?
Ah. Morning, Miss Clara.
You're awake at last.
You got the Tardis, then?
Military tactics. The Doctor is still missing
but he will always
come looking for his box.
By bringing it here, he will be lured
from the dangers of London
to this place of safety
and we will melt him with acid.
Okay, that last part?
And we will not melt him with acid.
Old habits.
- The Times. Shall I send it up?
- Yeah, why not?
Hah!
- Jenny!
- Ah, good morning, Clara.
Morning.
Um, so, what are we going to do?
Are we looking for the Doctor?
We've got the Paternoster Irregulars
out in force.
If anyone can find him, they can.
Meanwhile, Madam Vastra
is slightly occupied
by the Conk-Singleton forgery case
and is having the Camberwell
child-poisoner for dinner.
- For dinner?
- After she's finished interrogating him.
Probably best to stay out the larder.
It'll get a bit noisy in there later.
Um...
Ah, Miss Clara!
- You look better now you're up.
- Thank you, Strax!
No, sorry, trick of the light.
You still look terrible.
Can I get you anything?
- Uh, no, thanks. Maybe just some water.
- Of course.
Well, don't hold back,
I've nearly finished anyway.
Urn...
It's perfectly all right.
I washed in it myself.
All of a sudden, I'm not very thirsty.
Really?
Perhaps it is time, then...
For your mandatory medical examination!
- Say "ah".
- Ah.
- You didn't move your lips.
- You're looking at my eye.
Oh. Oh, yes, there we are, easy mistake.
Oh.
Now, that's interesting.
What? What's interesting?
Deflected narcissism,
traces of passive-aggressive
and a lot of muscular young men
doing sport.
What are you looking at?
Your subconscious.
Is that sport? It could be sport.
Well, stop looking.
Moving onto the thorax, such as it is...
Ah, excellent. Enviable spleen, well done.
Twenty-seven yea rs old,
with a projected life-span of exactly...
Stop right there!
Oh, you're going to do quite well.
But watch out for fluid retention later,
it's going to be spectacular.
Well, put your clothes back on.
They are on.
Oh, yes, so they are.
Why are you doing this?
If we are to serve together, I need you
in peak physical prowess, eh?
Ow! Why would we be serving together?
The Doctor's going to come back,
isn't he?
It is to be hoped.
He's not just going to abandon me here.
You must stop worrying
about him, my boy.
By now he's almost certainly
had his throat cut by the violent poor.
Bitey.
Bitey?
The air, it's bitey. It's wet and bitey.
Well, it's cold!
That's right. It's cold. It's cold.
I knew it was a thing.
I need, um, I need clothes.
I need clothes, that's what I need.
And a big, long scarf.
No, no, move on from that,
it looked stupid.
Uh, have you seen this face before?
No.
Are you sure?
Sir, I have never seen that face.
It's funny, because I'm sure that I have.
You know, I never know where the
faces come from. They just pop up.
Zap! Faces like this one. Come on, look
at it. Come and look, look, look, look.
Look, it's covered in lines.
But I didn't do the frowning.
Who frowned me this face?
Do you ever look in the mirror
and think "I've seen that face before"?
Yes.
Really? When?
Well, every time I look in the mirror.
Oh, yes, yes, fair enough, good point.
My face is fresh on, though.
Why this one?
Why did I choose this face?
It's like I'm trying
to tell myself something.
Like I'm trying to make a point.
But what is so important that I can't
just tell myself what I'm thinking?
I'm not just being rhetorical here.
- You can join in.
- I don't like it.
- What?
- Your face!
Well, I don't like it, either.
I mean, it's all right up until
the eyebrows, then it just goes haywire.
Look at the eyebrows!
These are attack eyebrows.
You could take bottle tops off with these!
They are mighty eyebrows indeed, sir.
They're cross! They're crosser
than the rest of my face.
They're independently cross!
They probably want to cede
from the rest of my face
and set up their own
independent state of eyebrows!
That's Scot... I am Scottish, aren't I?
I've gone Scottish.
Oh, yes, you are. You are definitely
Scots, sir. I hear it in your voice.
Oh, no, that's good. Oh.
Oh...
it's good I'm Scottish.
I'm Scottish. I am... Scottish.
I can complain about things, I can
really complain about things now.
- Give me your coat.
- No.
- I am cold.
- I'm cold.
I'm cold. There's no point in us
both being cold. Give me your coat!
Give me your coat!
No, wait. Shut up. Shut up.
Shut up! I missed something.
It was here, it was here. It was...
What was it I saw, what did I see?
This is what I saw!
Spontaneous combustion.
Oh! What devilry is this, sir?
I don't know.
But I probably blame the English.
Spontaneous combustion!
Is that like love at first sight?
Ha, a little.
It is the theory that human beings can,
with little or no inducement,
simply explode.
You don't need to flirt
with me, we're already married.
It's scientific nonsense, of course.
Marriage?
Hush! There have been nine
reported incidents
of people apparently
exploding in the last month.
And you think they weren't spontaneous?
I think whoever killed the dinosaur
had at least nine previous victims.
All of these perished
in the same spectacular fashion.
I thought you were painting me.
I was working.
Well, why am I posing, then?
Well, you brighten the room
tremendously. Chin up a little.
Oh, I don't understand
why I'm doing this.
Art?
Now, why destroy the victims
so completely?
It's difficult, it draws attention.
What advantage is to be gained?
Well, tell us, then.
Concealment, perhaps.
Concealment?
It's a fanciful theory but it fits the facts.
By destroying the body so completely,
you conceal what is missing from it.
Missing from the body?
Madame Vastra!
Clara! Excellent.
Pop your clothes on that chair there.
Look!
Advertisements, yes, so many.
It is a distressing modern trend.
No, look!
Look.
What?
The game is afoot.
We're going to need a lot of tea.
There appears to be
nothing of significance
in the rest of the newspaper,
not even in the agony column.
We can't know it's from the Doctor.
Of course it's from the Doctor.
The Impossible Girl,
that's what he calls me.
He says lunch but not when or where.
On the other side.
The other side of London? Bit vague.
The other side of regeneration, perhaps?
Once he's recovered?
So what am I supposed to do?
Guess where we're meeting?
Perhaps that's the point.
Perhaps you're supposed
to prove that you still know him.
Think what that must mean for a man
who barely knows himself.
It doesn't makes sense, he doesn't
do puzzles. He isn't complicated.
He really doesn't have
the attention span.
So...
keeping it dead simple,
on the other side...
What's wrong?
I don't know. Maybe the smell?
I know, it's everywhere.
Where did you get that coat?
I bought it.
From where?
- Uh, a shop.
- No.
Might've been a tramp.
You don't have any money.
I... I had a watch.
No! That watch was beautiful.
It was my favourite.
You swapped your favourite watch for
that coat? That's maybe not a good deal.
Well, I was in a hurry,
there was a terrible smell.
Okay.
No, no. Don't, don't... Don't, don't smile.
I will smile first and then
you know it's safe to smile.
- Are you cross with me?
- I am not cross!
But if I was cross,
it would be your fault and...
Yes, I am cross.
- I guessed that.
- I am extremely cross.
And if I hadn't changed my face,
would you be cross?
I would be cross if I wasn't cross!
- Why?
An ordinary person
wants to meet someone that they know
very well for lunch, what do they do?
Well, they probably
get in touch and suggest lunch.
Mmm-hmm. Okay.
So what kind of person would put
a cryptic note in a newspaper advert?
Well, I wouldn't like to say...
Oh, go on, do, say.
Well, I would say that that person
would be an egomaniac, needy,
game-player sort of person.
Thank you.
Well, at least that hasn't changed.
No, I don't suppose it ever will.
No, I don't suppose it will, either.
Clara, honestly,
I don't want you to change.
It was no bother, really.
I saw your advert,
I figured it out,
happy to play your game...
No, no. I didn't place the ad.
You placed the ad.
- No, I didn't.
- Yes.
You placed the ad, I figured
it out, Impossible Girl. See, lunch!
No, look. The Impossible...
That is a message
from the Impossible Girl.
For the Impossible Girl.
- Ooh.
- Ah. Hmm.
Well, if neither of us placed that ad,
who placed that ad?
Hang on. Egomaniac, needy game-player?
- This could be a trap.
- That was me?
- Never mind that.
- Yes, I am minding that.
- Clara.
- You were talking about me?
Clara, what is happening right now,
in this restaurant,
to you and me, is more
important than your egomania!
Nothing is more important
than my egomania!
Right, you actually said that!
You never mention that again!
It's... It's a vanity trap.
You're so busy congratulating
yourself on solving the puzzle,
you don't notice that you're
sticking your head in a noose.
What are you doing?
And that isn't the only grey one,
if you are having a cull.
What, do you have a
problem with the grey ones?
If I got new hair and it was grey,
I would have a problem.
- Yeah, I bet you would.
- Meaning?
It's too short.
Ow!
Sorry, it was the only one out of place.
I'm sure that you would want it killed.
Ooh, are you trying to
tell me something?
I'm trying to measure
the air disturbance in the room.
Right. Moments when
you know you are boring.
There is something extremely wrong
with everybody else sitting in this room.
Mmm, basically don't you
always think that?
Look at them. Don't look!
You just said to look!
Look without looking.
They look fine to me. They're just eating.
Are they?
Okay, no. No, they're not eating.
Something else they're not doing.
Breathing.
What do we do?
- Well, you don't want to eat, do you?
- I've slightly lost my appetite.
How long before
they notice that we're different?
Not long.
Anything we can do?
How long can you hold your breath?
We could casually stroll out of here,
like we changed our minds.
- Happens all the time.
- Of course it does.
We could take another look at the menu.
What are they?
I don't know. But don't worry,
because that's not the question.
The question is what is this restaurant?
Okay, what is this restaurant?
I don't know.
Ah, no sausages.
And there's no pictures, either.
Do you have a children's menu?
(A")! Specials?
Liver.
I don't like liver.
Spleen. Brain stern. Eyes.
Hmm... Is there a lot
of demand for those?
I don't think that's what's on the menu.
I think we are the menu.
Lungs. Skin.
Excuse me.
Okay. Robot in a mask.
It's a face.
Yeah, it's very convincing.
No. It's a face.
Yes.
- Yes, what?
- Yes, we have a children's menu.
You've got to admire their efficiency.
Is it okay if I don't?
Hello! Hello, are you the manager?
I demand to speak to the manager!
This is not a real restaurant, is it?
Well, it's more a sort of
an automated organ collection station
for the unwary diner.
Sweeney Todd without the pies.
So where are we now?
Factually, an ancient spaceship,
probably buried for centuries.
Functionally, a larder.
So, why hasn't somebody come for us?
- We're alive.
- We're alive. In a larder.
Exactly. It's cheaper than freezing us.
Okay.
Are you ready?
Go for it.
Don't let it roll away.
No.
We've got one shot at this.
Next time, make one that doesn't roll.
Go!
- Have you got it?
- I think I can just about reach it.
- It's at times like this I miss Amy.
- Who?
Nothing.
Ready?
Don't miss.
Oh!
Ooh.
Sorry, did I hit something?
Oh, the symbolism!
You should make that thing
voice-activated.
Oh, for God's sake. It is, isn't it?
I don't want to talk about it.
Doctor.
Dormant.
How do you know?
I don't. I'm just hoping.
So, is it these guys
that killed the dinosaur?
Well, if they're harvesting organs,
a dinosaur would have some great stuff.
Why would robots need organs?
Burke and Hare from space?
Maybe. That's a good theory.
Droids harvesting spare parts.
Ah, that rings a bell...
Captain! My Captain!
Can he see us?
Dormant.
Hoping?
Yep. Oh, look! He's recharging.
He's asleep, doesn't even
know we're here.
Are you sure?
Sure, not sure, one or the other.
Okay, so half man, half robot.
A cyborg, yeah?
- Oh.
- Oh?
- Ooh...
- Ooh?
Look at the hands.
What about them?
- Look at them.
- I'm looking.
They don't match. These hands don't
belong to the same body.
I don't understand.
Oh, I don't blame you.
See this, this is not your normal cyborg.
This isn't a man
turning itself into a robot.
This is a robot turning himself
into a man, piece by piece.
That's what the restaurant's for?
Well, it would need a constant
supply of spare parts.
You can tan skin but organs rot.
Some of that metal work, it looks Roman.
I wonder how long it's been around?
How much of the original is even left?
- The eyeballs look very fresh, though...
- Oh.
Is it awake?
It's waking up, I think.
Okay, let's go.
I've seen this before.
I'm missing something!
Doctor!
It's a brand-new head, rebooting.
Come on!
I've seen this before!
Oh! Hurry up. Get out.
Doctor!
Sorry, too slow. There's no point
in them catching us both.
Well, give me the screwdriver!
I might need it.
Oh, Doctor!
Something else they're not doing.
Breathing.
How long can you hold your breath?
Bring her.
All right, stop!
Stop! Stop it, all of you, now!
Ha, it's her first day.
If you don't stop it, I'm going to have
each and every single one of you
kicked out of this school.
Go on, then, do it!
Where is the other one?
There was another. Where is he?
Where is the other?
You will tell us or you will be destroyed.
What did you say?
You will tell us.
Yeah, I know. Or what?
You will die.
Go on, then. Do it.
Go on, then.
Do it.
I'm not going to answer
any of your questions.
So you have to do it. You have to kill me.
Threats don't work unless you deliver.
You will tell us where the other one is.
Nope.
- You will be destroyed.
- Destroy me, then.
And if you don't,
then I'm not going to believe a single
threat you make from now on.
Of course, if I'm dead,
then I can't tell you
where the other one went, then.
You need to keep this place
down here a secret, don't you?
Never start with your final sanction.
You've got nowhere to go but backwards.
Humans feel pain.
Bigger threat to smaller threat.
See what I mean? Backwards.
The information can be extracted
by means of your suffering.
Are you trying to scare me?
Because I'm already
bloody terrified of dying
and I will endure a lot of pain
for a very long time
before I give up the information
that is keeping me alive.
How long have you got?
All you can offer me is my life.
What you can't do is threaten it.
You can negotiate.
Okay, okay, okay, okay. Yes, yes, yes.
I am crying and it's just because
I am very frightened of you.
And if you know anything
about human beings,
that means you...
You're in a lot trouble.
We will not negotiate.
You don't have a choice.
I tell you what, I'll answer your questions
if you answer mine.
We will not answer questions.
We'll take turns, I'll go first.
Why did you kill the dinosaur?
We will not answer...
- Why did you kill the dinosaur?
- We will not answer questions!
Then you might as well kill me, because
I'm not talking again till you do.
Within the optic nerve of the dinosaur
is material of use
to our computer systems.
You burned a whole dinosaur
for a spare part?
No. Now, hang on.
You know what's in
a dinosaur's optic nerve,
which means you've seen them before.
Where is the other one?
How long have you been
rebuilding yourselves?
Look at the state of you!
Is there any real you left?
What's the point?
We will reach the promised land.
The...
The what, the promised land?
What's that?
Where is the other one?
I don't know.
But I know where he will be.
Where he will always be.
If the Doctor is still the Doctor,
he will have my back.
I'm right, aren't I?
Go on, please, please,
God, say I'm right.
Hello, hello, rubbish robots
from the dawn of time.
Thank you
for all the gratuitous information.
Five foot one and crying,
you never stood a chance.
Oh, stop it!
This is your power source
and feeble though it is,
I can use it to blow this whole room
if I see one thing that I don't like.
And that includes karaoke
and mime, so take no chances.
See, Clara? That's how you
disguise yourself as a Droid.
Yeah, well, I didn't have a lot of time.
I'd been suddenly abandoned.
Yeah, sorry. No, actually I'm not.
You're brilliant on adrenaline.
And you were out of your depth, sir.
Never try and control a control freak.
I am not a control freak!
Yes, ma'am.
- Why are you here?
- Why did you invite us?
The message in the paper.
That was you, wasn't it?
Oh.
I hate being wrong in public,
everybody forget that happened.
- Clara, say the word.
- What word?
They never sent you in here
without a word.
- I don't want to say it.
- I've guessed it already.
Geronimo!
Remain still and lay down your weapons,
in the name of the British Empire!
Strax!
- Sorry.
- I've told you before, take the stairs.
Oh, look. The cavalry.
I burned an ancient, beautiful
creature for one inch of optic nerve.
What do you think you can
accomplish, little man?
What do you? Vastra?
The establishment upstairs has been
disabled with maximum prejudice
and the authorities summoned.
Hang on, she called the police?
We never do that, we should start.
You see? Destroy us if you will,
they're still going to close
your restaurant.
That was going to sound better.
Then, we will destroy you.
No, you won't.
You are logical. You have restraint.
You kill to survive, you're not a murderer.
He's not a what?
This is a slaughterhouse.
How does that make it different
from any other restaurant?
You weren't vegetarian
the last time I checked.
This is over. Killing us won't change
that. What would be the point?
To find the promised land.
You're millions of years old,
it's time you knew. There isn't one.
I am in search of paradise.
Yeah? Well, me, too.
I'm not going to make it, either.
Doctor!
I will leave in the escape capsule.
Destroy where necessary.
Escape capsule? This ship is millions
of years old, it'll never fly.
- It has been repaired.
- What with?
You.
Defensive positions, everyone.
Doctor! He's getting away!
Your friend is intelligent.
He'll know better than to follow me.
Right, here we are, this is the place.
Come with me.
It is our intent to leave.
If it is your intent to stop us,
perhaps we should get down to business.
Dear Lord.
What has she landed us with this time?
The restaurant is closed.
Keep everyone out.
No one goes in there!
What are you doing?
I've got the horrible feeling
I'm going to have to kill you.
I thought you might appreciate
a drink first.
I know I would.
Watch out!
Fifty-first century, right?
Time-travelling space ship,
crashed in the past.
You're trying to get home
the long way round.
- I go to the promised land.
- So you keep saying.
Okay, so your restaurant
is made out of your old ship.
But you're wasting your time.
It can't ever fly.
The escape pod is viable.
How? You can't patch up
a spaceship with human remains.
You know, this really is ringing a bell.
Okay, that's clever.
How are you powering it?
Skin.
Get to the station. We need more men!
What shall I tell them is happening?
Go on!
How many do you estimate, my dear?
More than upstairs, about 20, 30?
The ones upstairs were mere decoys.
These are battle-ready.
I anticipate a challenge.
Don't worry, my boy, we shall die in glory!
Okay. Good-o!
"SS Marie Antoinette."
Out-of-control repair droids
cannibalising human beings.
I know that this is familiar but
I just... I just can't seem to place it.
How would you kill me?
Sister Ship of the Madame de Pompadour.
Nope, not getting it.
How would you kill me?
Why don't you have a drink first?
It's only human.
- I am not human.
- Neither am I.
Why can't you stay dead, coward?
What do you think of the view?
- I do not think of it.
- I don't think of it. I don't.
Droids and apostrophes,
I could write a book.
Except you are barely a droid any more.
There's more human in you than machine.
So tell me,
what do you think of the view?
It is beautiful.
No, it isn't. It's just far away.
Everything looks too small.
I prefer it down there.
Everything is huge.
Everything is so important.
Every detail, every moment.
Every life clung to.
How could you kill me?
For the same reason
that you're asking me that question,
because you don't really
want to carry on.
What'll happen to the other
droids when you die?
You're the control node, aren't you?
Presumably they'll deactivate.
I will not die.
I will reach the promised land.
There isn't any promised land.
This is just... It's a superstition
that you have picked up
from all the humanity
you've stuffed inside yourself.
I am not dead!
You are a broom.
Question, you take a broom,
you replace the handle
and then later you replace the brush.
And you do that over and over again.
Is it still the same broom?
Answer, no, of course it isn't.
But you can still sweep the floor.
Which is not strictly relevant,
skip that last part.
You have replaced every piece of
yourself, mechanical and organic,
time and time again.
There's not a trace
of the original you left.
You probably can't even remember
where you got that face from.
It cannot end.
It has to. You know it does.
And there's only one way out.
Self-destruction is against
my basic programme.
Murder is against mine!
Jenny!
Hold your breath! They're stupid,
everybody hold their breath.
I can't do it. I can't.
Be brave, my love.
I can store oxygen in my lungs.
Share with me!
- You are stronger than you look.
- I'm hoping you are, too.
This is over.
Are you capable of admitting that?
Do you have it in you to murder me?
Those people down there,
they are never small to me.
Don't make assumptions about
how far I will go to protect them,
because I've already come
a very long way.
And unlike you, I don't expect
to reach the promised land.
You realise, of course, one of us
is lying about our basic programming?
Yes.
And I think we both know who that is.
Stop!
Whoa.
You're sure he'd come back here?
There was no trace of him
in the wreckage.
They searched all of Parliament Hill.
Where else would he go?
I fear we have missed him.
Please, come in.
I'm... I'm not interrupting?
I should be glad of your company.
What can I do for you?
Ah, well, that's exactly
what I was going to ask you.
Seems like I'm stuck here now.
Got a vacancy?
You would be very welcome
to join our little household.
But I have it on the highest authority
that the Doctor will be
returning for you very soon.
Whose authority?
The person who knows him
best in all the universe.
And who's that?
Miss Clara Oswald,
who, perhaps has, by instinct,
already dressed to leave?
I just wanted a change of clothes.
I don't think I know
who the Doctor is any more.
It would seem, my dear,
you're very wrong about that.
Clara!
Give him hell. He'll always need it.
You've redecorated.
Yes.
- I don't like it.
- Not entirely convinced myself.
I think there should be more
round things on the walls.
I used to have lots of round things.
I wonder where I put them?
I'm the Doctor.
I've lived for over 2,000 years
and not all of them were good.
I've made many mistakes
and it's about time
that I did something about that.
Clara, I'm not your boyfriend.
I never thought you were.
I never said it was your mistake.
What do you think?
- Who put that advert in the paper?
- Who gave you my number?
A long time ago, remember?
You were given the number
of a computer helpline
and you ended up phoning the Tardis.
Who gave you that number?
The woman. The woman in the shop.
Then there's a woman out there who is
very keen that we stay together.
How do you feel on the subject?
Am I home?
If you want to be.
I'm sorry.
I'm so, so sorry.
But I don't think I know
who you are any more.
You'd better get that.
It might be your boyfriend.
Shut up. I don't have a boyfriend.
Hello?
- Hello?
- It's me.
Yes, it's you, who's this?
It's me, Clara. The Doctor.
What do you mean, "the Doctor"?
I'm phoning you from Trenzalore.
- I don't...
- From before I changed.
I mean, it's all still to happen for me.
It's coming. Oh, it's a-coming.
Not long now.
I can feel it.
Why? Why would you do this?
Because I think
it's going to be a Whopper.
And I think you might be scared.
And however scared you are, Clara,
the man you are with right now,
the man I hope you are with,
believe me, he is more scared than
anything you can imagine right now.
And he... He needs you.
So who is it?
Is that the Doctor?
Yes.
He sounds old.
Please tell me I didn't get old.
Anything but old!
I was young.
Oh! Is he grey?
Yes.
Clara, please, hey? For me?
Help him. Go on.
And don't be afraid.
Goodbye, Clara.
Miss you.
Well?
Well what?
He asked you a question.
Will you help me?
You shouldn't have been listening.
I wasn't. I didn't need to.
That was me talking.
You can't see me, can you?
You look at me and you can't see me.
Have you any idea what that's like?
I'm not on the phone, I'm right here.
Standing in front of you.
Please, just...
just see me.
Thank you.
For what?
Phoning.
I don't think
that I'm a hugging person now.
I'm not sure you get a vote.
Whatever you say.
This isn't my home, by the way.
Sorry, I'm sorry about that. I missed.
- Where are we?
- Glasgow, I think.
Ah, you'll fit right in. Scottish.
Right, shall we, uh...
Do you want to go and get
some coffee or chips or something?
Or chips and coffee?
Coffee. Coffee would be great.
You're buying.
I don't have any money.
You're fetching, then.
I'm not sure that I'm the fetching sort.
Yeah, still not sure you get a vote.
Hello!
I'm Missy. You made it!
I hope my boyfriend
wasn't too mean to you.
Boyfriend?
Now, did he push you
out of that thing or did you fall?
I couldn't really tell.
He can be very mean sometimes.
Except to me, of course.
Because he loves me so much.
I do like his new accent, though.
I think I might keep it.
Where am I?
Where do you think you are?
Look around you. You made it.
The promised land. Paradise!
Welcome to Heaven!
- Where the hell have you been?
- It's not my fault, I got distracted.
- By what?
- You can always find something. Come on!
- Where are we going?
- Into darkness.
Welcome to the most dangerous
place in the universe.
They're coming! They're coming!
Aristotle!
The enemy are right on top of us!
I'm sorry.
Exterminate! Doctor!